BRYAN HANKINS

♦ Email: <u>bryanhankinswork@gmail.com</u>

♦ Address: Evansville, IN 47720

◆ Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryan-hankins-8668811ab/

♦ Portfolio: https://bryanhankins.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

Senior frontend developer with over six years of professional experience in web development. During that time, I have been acknowledged as a solution-focused professional with the ability to design and develop innovative applications using advanced technologies. I collaborated closely with the application team to develop and implement many full-stack web applications, ensuring optimal functionality, quality, and reliability.

SKILLS —		
- JavaScript	- Typescript	- CI/CD
- React/Redux	- Bootstrap	- AWS
- Vue/Vuex	- HTML/CSS	- GitHub
- Next.js	- Material UI	- Angular
- GraphQL	- RESTful API	- Wordpress
- Node.js	- MongoDB	- AWS
- Jest	- MySQL	

WORK HISTORY -

Sr. Web Developer GeoTech Solutions | Newburgh, IN

05/2022 - Present

- Built multi-page web and mobile application with a React, CSS, HTML, and JavaScript to style layout for homepage, checkout page, and dashboard.
- Made the most crucial pages fully responsive, whereas before some were up to completely unusable on mobile.
- Automated provisioning and maintained many servers on AWS instances and created complete CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins.
- Implemented Stripe to wire into a checkout form that handles API calls for credit card transactions.
- Processed user Firebase authentication with email and password to allow user access to their profile, with strong encryption for secure user's data protection.
- Migrated Vue.js based application to the React/TypeScript, Styled-components web application.

React Frontend Developer

- Implemented all aspects of web development process, including UI development, API integration, deployment and testing tasks using React, Node and RESTful APIs.
- Developed client-side apps with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and React and thoroughly tested the web app throughout development to ensure optimal user experience.
- Created a flexible, maintainable, and extendable codebase and be familiar with object-oriented design and programming patterns.
- Used Material-UI, React Bootstrap, One-way data flow, Virtual DOM, JSX with React Flux architecture to build attractive and reusable UI.
- Used Node with a bit of express for the backend alongside React to handle the complex frontend functionality.

$\textbf{Frontend Developer} \hspace{3cm} 08/2019 - 11/2020$

BNY | Evansville, IN

- Utilized JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, JSON, and CSS to design and deploy company website with integrated Web Service APIs for Quick-books and open-source scheduling application.
- Worked with back-end engineers to ensure that API endpoints were designed thoughtfully and easy to integrate into the frontend.
- Rapidly provided a user-friendly solution for wrapping a legacy SQL database-driven project held by the company into an easy-to-use web application using JavaScript.
- Developed dynamic web pages using HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, jQuery, React.js, Bootstrap, Less, CSS3, SASS and AJAX.

Web Developer 07/2017 – 08/2019

Freelancer | Remote

- Developed the front end for a virtual lab/eCommerce site to sell chemicals using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Redux and GraphQL.
- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, jQuery, and JavaScript.
- Developed various screens for the front end using JavaScript and used various predefined components from NPM and CSS libraries.
- Implemented HTTP REST API using Node.JS and extensively tested RESTful services using POSTMAN.

EDUCATION —